A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society, Office Files of Irena Gross FA588
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society, Office Files of Irena Gross
1994-2003
Rockefeller Archive Center
Grudzińska-Gross, Irena
Ford Foundation
FA588
3.93 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Alphabetical.
Scope and Contents
Includes but not limited to: administrative records, general files, correspondence, meeting records, budgets and program reviews.
Biographical / Historical
Irena Grudzinska Gross is a historian of East European literature and culture who worked for several years at the Ford Foundation. From 1998 to 2003, she was a Program Officer in the Ford Foundation's Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society unit (GCS) and was responsible for grantmaking related to Eastern and Central Europe.
Gross taught courses on East European literature and history at Princeton University. Books she has published include "Golden Harvest" (with her husband Jan T. Gross) and "Czeslaw Milosz and Joseph Brodsky: Fellowship of Poets". She earned her Ph.D. from Columbia University.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
- American Governance Seminar, 2001 January 19 (Box 1)
- Berresford, Susan, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
- Budget Old, 2001 (Box 1)
- Budzet, 2000-2003 (Box 1)
- CARESBAC, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
- Conflict Related Grantmaking, 2000 (Box 1)
- Constitutionalism, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
- Consultation (Women's Rights), 1998 October 16 (Box 1)
- Contact Office in Poland, 2000 (Box 1)
- Descriptions of Current Ford Programming on Police, 1998 February (Box 1)
- Eastern Europe -- Eastern Europe, 1994-1997 (Box 1)
- Eastern Europe -- Program Assistants, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
- Eastern Europe -- Eastern Europe -- USAID, 1997 (Box 1)
- Eastern Europe -- East Europe Trip -- June Zeitlin, 1998 March 28-April 3 (Box 1)
- East Europe Second Visit, 1998 (Box 1)
- Education Consultancy Letters, 1999 (Box 1)
- Edwards, Michael, 2000 (Box 1)
- Field Statements, 2000 (Box 1)
- Ford Foundation Transitional Justice Meeting, 2000 April 6 (Box 1)
- Foundation on Inter-Ethnic Relations (FIER), 1998 (Box 1)
- Freedom of Expression/Journalism Convening (Aspen Institute), 2000 (Box 1)
- Higher Education Consultancy (1/2), 1999 (Box 1)
- Higher Education Consultancy (2/2), 1999 (Box 1)
- Judicial Reform, 1998 (Box 1)
- Matei, Liviu -- Central European University, 2001 (Box 1)
- Nowakowska, Urszula, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
- OSKA, 1999 (Box 1)
- Peace and Social Justice Conference, 1998 (Box 1)
- Peace and Social Justice Worldwide Meetings, 1998-2000 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Among other items, this file contains Report #015010 - Peace and Social Justice Program Worldwide Meeting, June 4-9 2000: Rapporteur's report / PSJ.
- Peace and Social Justice Program Staff Retreat, 1997 (Box 1)
- Philanthropy, 1998 (Box 1)
- Philanthropy Learning Group, 2002 February 26-27 (Box 1)
- Poland and Slovakia First Visit (J. Zeitlin and I. Gross), 1998 March 27-April 9 (Box 1)
- Poland Trip, 1999 April 4-10 (Box 2)
- Police Work, 1999 (Box 2)
- Program Assessment, 1998 March 23-25 (Box 2)
- Program Budget, 2002 (Box 2)
- Program Review, 1998 (Box 2)
- Rekosh, Ed, 1998 (Box 2)
- Rekosh, Edwin, 1999-2001 (Box 2)
- Russia and East European Program, 1991-1996 (Box 2)
- Serban, Mihaela, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
- Serbia, 1999 (Box 2)
- Slovakia -- CPPI, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
- South Africa world Conference Against Racism, 2001 (Box 2)
- Stefan Batory, 1995-1998 (Box 2)
- Stefan Batory Foundation, 2002 (Box 2)
- Stroud, Susan, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
- Szelenyi, Ivan, 1998-2000 (Box 2)
- Tenny, Buzz, 1998 (Box 2)
- Think Tanks, 1998 (Box 2)
- Tibbitts, Felisa, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
- Trust for a Civil Society -- General, 1998 (Box 2)
- Trust for a Civil Society -- General, 1999 (Box 2)
- Trust for a Civil Society -- Board of Trustees Meeting, 1999 September 30 (Box 2)
- Trust for a Civil Society -- Board of Trustees Meeting, 1999 November 7 (Box 2)
- Trust for a Civil Society -- Trust for a Civil Society Meeting, 2000 January 19 (Box 2)
- Trust for a Civil Society -- Board of Trustees Meeting, 2000 June 16 (Box 2)
- Trust for a Civil Society -- Board of Trustees Meeting, 2000 October 13 (Box 2)
- Trust for a Civil Society -- Meeting Notes, 2000 (Box 2)
- Trust for a Civil Society -- Presentation to the Board, 2000 April 18 (Box 3)
- USAID Trust Fund, 1998 (Box 3)
- US Government -- Private Foundations Meeting, 1997 April 3 (Box 3)
- VERA Institute Workshop on Police in Democratic Societies, 1998 March (Box 3)
- Visits, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
- Women, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
- Worldwide Philanthropy Group Meeting, 2000 January 5-7 (Box 3)
- Zeitlin, June -- Old E. Europe Files, 1998 (Box 3)
- Zeitlin, June -- Trip, 1999 (Box 3)